Brian Allison

818-326-9899 brian.keith.allison@gmail.com

PROFILE

Well-rounded professional with excellent work ethics, a balance of technical and creative skills with extensive experience in graphic design for print and web applications. Creative direction and management of an award-winning newspaper, website, and magazines, as well as advertising and marketing materials. Significant expertise in adopting transformative technology, innovating to reduce costs and increase efficiency, and managing company-wide change.

STRENGTHS

- Graphic design
- Project management
- Package design
- Print and web creative
- Information technology management
- Cost control/budget management
- eCommerce Marketing
- Staff and vendor relations

EXPERIENCE

Marketing/Design/Operations

American Cycle Systems (ACS) Monrovia, CA September 2021 – Present

Oversee operations for bicycle parts and accessory manufacturer. Responsible for marketing and design collateral for web and print, including package design. Implement marketing campaigns, product listings, and catalogs on various web platforms. Handle customer service correspondence, order processing, shipping, warranty, and returns.

Main Responsibilities

- Platform Marketing: Administer product and brand campaigns through Google Ads, Amazon Vendor, Amazon Seller, Ebay, and Shopify.
- Amazon: Manage Amazon catalogs for Seller and Vendor accounts. Creation of A+ content, storefront and product listings.
- Photography: Product photography, photoshop editing, and color correction for web implementation.
- eCommerce: Shopify site creation, HTML & CSS theme code editing for unique customization of pages.
- Package Design: Design and prepare packaging for print, including all product photography and technical illustrations necessary.
- Instructions: Create product instructions for print and web applications.
- Event Collateral: Create trade show displays & collateral for exhibit booths and events.

Tech Line Analyst, Powersports Division

American Honda Corporation Torrance, CA August 2020 – August 2021

Assist technicians with electrical and mechanical troubleshooting and repair on all Honda Power Sports products. Primarily assisting technicians, service writers, and service managers.

Main Responsibilities

- Technical Direction: Provided direction for difficult repairs including instruction on procedures, diagnostics, and troubleshooting techniques.
- Warranty Processing: Authorized warranty work, processed claims.
- Claim-Filing Assistance: Provide labor-op codes, negotiating straight labor times, and warrantable parts for dealer submission.
- Dealer Assistance: Regarding recalls, improvement campaigns, and parts.

Art Director

Los Angeles Downtown News Los Angeles, CA August 1996 – March 2020

Lead all graphic design for the preeminent news source for downtown Los Angeles, including a weekly newspaper, three annual magazines, a website, and marketing materials.

Main Responsibilities

- Project Management: Plan and delegate assignments with writers, photographers, and designers to maintain schedules, stay within budgets, and meet tight deadlines.
- Production Management: Direct layout, design, art, and images for weekly and annual publications. Catalog and tag thousands of images supplied by freelancers on assignment for quick database access.
- Ad Design: Oversee in-house creative; work closely with clients, sales representatives, and designers to create effective advertising for print and web. Create copy as needed.
- Ad Trafficking: Manage traffic flow of all advertising, in-house ad creative, and preflight, as well as correction/editing of print-ready files.
- Marketing/Promotion: Design and create promotional material for in-house sales, social media, and email campaigns, including drafting content as needed. Create logos and marketing themes for annual publications and large-scale collateral for company events.
- Print Management: Coordinate the printing of heat-set and open-web publications. Solicit quotes; evaluate paper, trim, and press options to manage cost and quality. Press-check publications for quality control.
- Illustration: Create both traditional and computer-generated illustration, including technical illustrations, infographics, maps, and diagrams.
- Photography: Provide photography for various advertising, editorial, and in-house needs. Plan visual direction; manage photographers on photo shoots.
- Video: Edit raw footage, still images, and audio files for production clips and presentations.

SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

InDesign, Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere Pro, Bridge CC, Acrobat, Pit Stop Pro, Keynote, PowerPoint, Word, Excel, Quark Xpress, and various other Adobe CC design, print, web, and video applications. Also proficient in HTML and CSS.

EDUCATION

Art Institute of Pittsburgh Associates Degree, Visual Communications